<journal name="journal maker...journal">
    <entry  time="2025-06-04T00:03Z">
        <overview> loose specification written </overview>
        <challenges></challenges>
        <newConcepts></newConcepts>
        <thoughts>
            trying not to overwhelm myself here. need to break up tasks into smaller ones, smaller achievements - create a rudimentary working application, and iterate on that.
        </thoughts>
    </entry>

    <entry name="second" time="2025-06-04T00:39Z">
        <overview>
            I began with converting this journal thus far as an xml document, to have a model entry and/or journal item to work with.
            new concepts learned/used:
            XML documents must have a root element wrapping everything. It is not assumed that the document itself is the root element.
        </overview>
        <challenges></challenges>
        <newConcepts></newConcepts>
        <thoughts>
            I suppose this app should take the form of a web app launched locally, reading in files or creating new ones, and then adding to or removing the entries and exporting the product as needed. I wonder if there are risks with safety or data integrity with this approach.

            I should probably add validation constraints to the xml later down the line, not integral so will not waste time on it now.
        </thoughts>
    </entry>

    <entry  time="2025-06-04T13:18Z">
        <overview></overview>
        <challenges>
            Inadvertently discovering alternate methods of achieving this goal, ones that might render a lot of my methods unnecessary. Like, perhaps using XSL to display the journals, rather than parsing and processing the XML files and displaying it using HTML - that would require quite a left turn, and I'd prefer to stick to what I know, applying and reinforcing my current knowledge and proficiency in the tools I do possess. 
            but aren't we as software engineers meant to value efficiency over all?
            putting this thought to the back of my mind for now.
        </challenges>
        <newConcepts></newConcepts>
        <thoughts>
            later down the line, add functionality for json as an alternative (starting thinking I should have used json from the start, but this idea is better, maybe I could even make conversion an option - export either to json or xml)
        </thoughts>
    </entry>
</journal>